Petr Zankov

1020 Renens Switzerland **☎** +41 78 850-95-57 ⋈ petr.zankov@gmail.com

Summary

Specialization Systems software engineer

Software Assembler (x86, x86, 64, PowerPC, ARM, SIMD), C, C++, C#, Python, skills GNU Toolchain (gcc, gdb and others), LLVM, Git, LaTeX, Visual studio, Doxygen, Shell scripts (bash, batch, PowerShell), IDA, GTK, OpenGL, OpenAL, OpenCV, WiX Toolset, Django, Linux kernel drivers, Windows kernel drivers, embedded systems, Symbolic binary execution, Static binary analysis

Hardware FPGA (Verilog, circuit diagrams), microcontrollers (AVR, ARM), skills PCB layout (Mentor graphics, manual)

Experience

2014-present Software engineer, Dependable Systems Lab, EPFL, Lausanne, Switzerland.

Integrated the S^2E symbolic execution engine with a fuzzer:

- implemented both S²E-to-fuzzer and fuzzer-to-S²E PoV exchange
- o allowed to discover 30% more bugs in the same time frame

Automated proof of vulnerability generation with the S²E symbolic execution engine:

- allowed seamless PoV generation for every bug discovered in the binary
- introduced no overhead to the execution process
- successfully used in a CTF security competition

Developed a memory bugs detection technique based on S²E symbolic execution engine:

- utilizes novel metadata propagation approach
- allows dynamic detection of memory violations
- o gives zero false positives with a real world applications

2012–2014 Software engineer, LLC "WISE-Technique", Zhukovskij, Russia.

Developed a microkernel real time operating system with ARINC 653 and POSIX(partial) layers. Following features were implemented from scratch:

- o OS kernel
- o multi-arch and multi-core support for PowerPC and IA-32
- o drivers for PCI, SATA, Ethernet
- debugging environment (based on KVM and GDB)

Developed kernel drivers and user space software for the helicopter flight recorder:

- implemented an ARINC653 API layer for the common kernel drivers
- o deployed RTOS on cutomer's embedded hardware system

2012–2012 Software engineer, FSUE "Flight Research Center", Zhukovskij, Russia. Migrated 3D rendering engine from X11 to Wayland. Also enhanced performance

by reimplementing functions using SIMD instructions.

2008–2012 **Software engineer**, JSC "V.V. Tikhomirov Scientific Research Institute of Instrument Design", Zhukovskij, Russia.

Developed software for civil sonar data acquisition and analysis. Full software stack starting from FPGA firmware and up to GUI applications was implemented:

- FPGA firmware for signal synthesis and digitizing
- FPGA device driver for Linux
- o user space cross-platform software for sonar control and data processing
- o real time data acquisition, processing and layout

Education

- 2011 Master of Applied Mathematics and Physics, Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, Russia.
- 2009 Bachelor of Applied Mathematics and Physics, Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, Russia.

Languages

French Basic communication skills

English Upper Intermediate

Russian Native

Hobbies

Big mountain freeride skiing, freestyle skiing, radio electronics

Last update: December 13, 2016